but inductee for tonight is going to be
Mr Alex
let's ask you and he will end up
watch me Nino unless they make their
wishes
for the publisher that didn't play
dealer and is the driving force behind
serving a cultural world
[Applause]
honorees
public servants distinguished guests
ladies and gentlemen
it is my great pleasure to present South
Euclid mayor Georgie WeMo for induction
into the 2023 class of Hall of Fame
honorees
[Applause]
I'd also like to extend my
congratulations to all of this year's
exceptional on a race and passed One
release
for making tonight possible
however before I say any more
about mayor Willow and her outstanding
accomplishments
which you can read in more detail in the
program I want to recognize Dorothy and
Sam coso your James parents who raised
her in the Serbian Church Center of life
Dorothy and Sam please stand up and do
it tomorrow
earlier today I was in a church service
with our Bishop Serbian Bishop of the
Eastern diocese to our James Bishop my
bishop and a monastery in in Richfield
and George Ames his grace asked me to
convey his personal
heartfelt congratulations for tonight
for your honor and all the Great
accomplishments that you have achieved
throughout Georgia's high school and
college Years at Akron University
duojan was active in Serbian Sports
choral singing and dance ensembles
Georgine was a Serbian Sunday school
teacher and also served as principal of
the Serbia Sunday School
this first woman elected mayor of the
city of South Euclid is never too busy
to promote her Serbian Heritage and
culture she worked with me to bring the
Belgrade Philharmonic Orchestra to
perform a severance hall for the benefit
of the Serbian cultural Garden
Georgie helped raise funds for the
Serbian Hill and their Monastery at
Mount apples which was nearly completely
destroyed the fire was so tense as it
burned down after that Monastery that
one of the monks was told this saying
even the stones were crying in sympathy
this concert by the famous magandy
Orchestra Belgrade was a sell-off the
severance Hall and helped significantly
with rebuilding the monastery
she sought a grant from the Ohio Arts
Council and sponsored the Lila Nicholas
Orchestra from Novi Sad Serbia to
perform at Notre Dame college for the
benefit again of the Serbian cultural
Garden
has hosted many academic political and
cultural groups of Serbia and has worked
with the Ohio National Guard on many
civilian Serbian projects in 2019 when
the Serbian cultural Garden hosted the
nationalization program on the main
stage during one world day Georgine did
an excellent job as a missed Christmas
ceremonies
mayor Velo has been involved in over 30
professional activities and over 20
Civic activities serving as president
chairperson or board member for all of
her magnificent efforts Georgie has been
awarded many many awards and way way too
many to mention here tonight
with all of her many activities Georgine
took time out to have two wonderful Sons
harder and miles and with her
daughters-in-law she enjoys four
grandchildren
now Georgine also
was responsible for the work that went
on in the Serbian Youth Camp in
Northwestern Pennsylvania known as shade
land
this is probably the oldest and largest
Youth Camp certain Youth Camp in the
nation in the effort she enlisted her
husband of 45 years Carter wheeler to do
the heavy work now Carter owns True
Value Hardware Store in South Euclid if
you see Carter in July he may give you a
very very special deal on a snowboard
mayor willow also organized many Serbian
and cultural events including the annual
Serbian festival at St Sava Serbia
Cathedral and in Parma she was crowned
Miss gaglish in her early years and
thereafter spent many years promoting
Serbian Heritage and culture
Georgie
I know you're familiar with this because
maybe not everyone but some of you know
God have heard of schliberalness
this little bit is a plum Serbian film
brand
a somewhat powerful alcohol which if
you're not careful and you drink too
much of it it'll make you take back
things you never stole
now when I was publisher of the plane
dealer I ignored Brokers and had don't
tolerance for inaccurate information
so I want to put the record straight
tonight
Georgine Rio was not the queen of
slitherovitz in 1909.
it was 1908 during the model recession
ladies and gentlemen I want to welcome
my good friend and our great great
servant Ambassador please welcome mayor
George and Rio
[Applause]
[Music]
so um
little does anybody know this fight so I
am the oldest of four children and you
know usually the oldest things happen in
the house that don't happen for the
other children so when my parents were
moving my mother handed me my baby book
which I'm sure my sister's channel is
here and she knows she doesn't have one
but so my mom hands me this baby book
and it's in a box and we're looking at
it and as we open it up there's a
picture and it says Georgine's first
visitors and who was holding me on the
couch visiting my parents but Alex was
has been very important
um his son lacks his son Michael and
John
his lovely wife Carol and um his
children's mother Sylvia and I can't
tell you that's what
that's what our culture is about for
everybody of us in here is those
relationships have become family
because without that
we're really not who we are so Alex I
want to thank you and the entire
Majestic family for being part of our
Coastal path
I felt like after release
your Braves Bishop molestick
the elected officials in this room gets
family friends
and tonight I have here my mentor read
from Global Cleveland our assami from
Indonesia
congratulations to my fellow 2023
classmates I'm very honored to be
inducted with each and every one of you
as you are so well deserving
I'd like to thank my parents Sam and
Dorothy coso who are with me tonight my
grandparents my Aunts Uncles and Kuma
Lee for raising me in the Slovenian
Serbian Village of Cleveland Ohio
mom and dad who instilled in us our
Serbian Heritage and Eastern Orthodox
Faith which has been the building blocks
of my life and my siblings it is because
of my upbringing that I stand here today
inducted into the Cleveland
International holiday
who would have ever imagined it and I'm
so grateful that my parents are here to
see it
thank you to my husband Carter who has
embraced on my crazy ethnic behavior and
my sister Tiana who's here celebrating
with with me my sons Carter and Miles my
daughter-in-law Aaron my my daughter
couldn't be here and neither could my
daughter-in-law or my two brothers but
they're on with me and they're hoping
when it's a talk short
also the last group that I really have
to thank being here tonight too is
myself and the family I see residents
here I see my fellow the wife of
business experience
and you know they allowed me to do all
these things and and I just can't thank
them enough
each and every one of us in this room
represent different heritages Customs
traditions and experiences we make up
the fabric of the region and we share a
bond of integration that has lasted
centuries
and is celebrated each year on one world
day in our Cleveland cultural Gardens
as a child to Serbian language is spoken
we watched lambs and pigs churn out a
spit in our backyard and my mother's
home was filled with my aunt's uncles
and cousins in fact it took three CDs to
actually feed the coastal family
celebrations and our Serbian cathedrals
of medicine holidays I love the smell of
my bubba strudel celebrating our special
Christmas lava singing serving songs and
learning our traditional folklore dances
growing up I thought this is what all
things were like
but as we know each family's Heritage
and traditions tell a story we learn as
adults that the customs and traditions
that we were taught will impact our
lives and will be with us always
an example of this was my parents and my
sister Chad and I traveled to Serbia
with my father's male court with serving
events called where one evening we
arrived by bus very late to the city of
trevia it probably somewhere between 11
and 12 and while everybody was in line
getting the room because they were
exhausted my sister and I could hear out
on on the patio that there was a poll
that started which is serving dance we
could we could hear the music going so
we dropped our bags and we ran out onto
this Pavilion and we just grab the hands
of old strangers and entered the circle
many of that matter Stephanie thought
about this never once did we stop and
think she'll be join in no it was
Instinct the sheer fact that though we
were raised here in Cleveland Ohio we
knew the same dance steps as those that
were raised in Serbia
I think that about leadership in
Cleveland a wonderful program you have
here in Cleveland
and a fellow classmate had heard that I
was Serbian and approached me during one
of the sessions and said to me that she
was Croatian and that her Bubba made a
dish and would I know it and so of
course
um
she gave she told me what the what the
dish was and you know the surgery and
croatians would be wrong kind of the
same it was definitely stable in our
family and the next day I came in and
handed her that recipe
and then you know on Facebook she's
showing everybody she's making it and so
now I've become
um the person she leans on for all her
traditional cultural dishes and they
stopped and they say to myself if it
wasn't for what I learned from my family
in church and my kumabi I couldn't have
passed that on to someone who never
learned and for me I think that talks
volumes about what what we're about in
this room
these are just a few examples of why
it's so important that we continue to
pass down throughout the generations
recipes stories memories of where we
came from because if not not only will
our our family
history you look at me
it will also be Cleveland's history that
will never be brought totally before and
I'm so excited Dan and Alex about our
opportunities at the Museum I had called
Dan a few weeks ago and I didn't know
that he had actually spoken to the
director and I had an opportunity to ask
questions and I asked
what is the Western Reserve of
historical's connection to the cultural
Museum into all of us and our
nationalities in the world and she said
oh
he said I don't know if you know this
man but his name is Danny Hanson and I
was just on the phone with them and I
said who doesn't understand so Dan thank
you
so it's it's up to all of us in this
room to continue the legacy of our
family's Heritage and build upon it
never ever ever forget it I want to ask
you tonight will you raise your hand if
you received Dan Hansen's people
clevelandpeople.com email every week
okay so if you are not on the list
clevelandpeople.com and I'm going to
challenge you
see this email
that tells you all about what's going on
every week that our International
Community explore a tradition or a
culture that is different from males
take your family and friends for a walk
including culture Gardens and maybe
eat basket can sit amongst the different
cultures and break bread as we did
tonight because the one thing all our
cultures love is good food hospitality
I'd like to thank the international Hall
of Fame committee and especially the
dynamic duo of Dan and Debbie Hansen
we miss your mother Pat and I know she's
looking down on us and I can feel her
and I know she's proud of me
for the art joy and such and esteem
group
of individuals and all of you who came
to celebrate with us I want to say thank
you in closing each of our different
International cultures our thin thread
that together we use the city of
Cleveland into a dynamic welcoming
Community filled with new and old
customs and stories that's allowing us
to become one community
something I know we're all proud of
and so I'm so honored to be part of
tonight's International Event and to be
part of this International City and I'm
humbled to be placed in the 2023
Cleveland International Hall of Fame
because I know one thing this is for my
brother my dad you're some good
emotional my prayer father my papa and
my daddy because they're the ones who
came here and who brought us to
Cleveland and that's why we're part of
this great interest foreign